# Warren Ehrenfried

2706 Kingsland Ct. Kingsport, TN 37660 423-765-5569 wehrenfr@vols.utk.edu

## **SUMMARY**

I am a Junior at the University of Tennessee in Knoxville majoring in geology with a minor in economics. I am an undergraduate research assistant in the geology department and I have a passion for creating geologic maps as well as the economics related to geology. I am now working on further developing my skills in GIS and also in R and applying these skills to real world problems.

## **EDUCATION**

## **University of Tennessee**

Knoxville, TN

Expected graduation, May 2020

- GPA: 3.80
- Major: Geology
- Minor: Economics
- Studying abroad in Barcelona for Spring 2019 semester
- Dean's List
- HOPE Scholar
- Undergraduate Research Assistant

Dobyns-Bennett Kingsport, TN

High School Diploma, May 2016

- Vice President of Investors Club Junior and Senior year
- Met with Tennessee congressman Phil Roe for starting Investors Club
- 4.15 GPA
- School and club soccer team

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

## **University of Tennessee**

**Knoxville, TN** 

Research Assistant

May 2018 - Present

- Work in Professor Nick Dygert's lab studying petrology
- Study Kimberlite xenoliths examining formation pressures and temperatures
- Created thin sections of kimberlitic rock from Siberian kimberlites, task included using rock saw, grinding and polishing of the rock, and gluing to the glass thin section
- Used SEM and Electron Microprobe to examine weight percentages of the rock
- Performed grain size piezometry using thousands of olivine grains to calculate stress intensities
- Compared piezometry data to thermobarometry data to find the estimated formation pressure and temperature of these kimberlitic rocks
- Presented results at Discovery Day 2018
- Created erosion potential map of the Sun Valley, Idaho region using GIS, created poster and presented findings

**Four Points by Sheraton Hotel** 

Knoxville, TN

- Parking guests' vehicles and returning their keys
- Assisting with front desk and housekeeping duties when required
- Retrieving guests' vehicles and taking luggage to and from their rooms

## **Ridgefields Country Club**

**Kingsport, TN** *Summer 2016-2017* 

Head Lifeguard

- Tasked with running a lifeguard team and helped organize schedules
- Keeping pH, chlorine, and other chemicals at suitable levels

Jimmy Johns Kingsport, TN

Sandwich Maker Aug 2014 – Aug 2016

## **SKILLS**

- Geographical Information Systems (GIS)
- Risk Mapping
- Electron Microprobe and SEM
- Limited proficiency in Python and R
- Creation of thin section rock layers for use on petrographic microscope
- CPR and AED certified
- Limited working proficiency in Spanish

## **VOLUNTEER HISTORY**

- 160 hours volunteered for John's Island, South Carolina mission trip
- Participated in building projects for First Broad Street United Methodist Church such as roofing and constructing several wheelchair ramps